Guide to the Eleanor Robson Belmont Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Subject Files, 1904-1979
  - Burnett, Frances Hodgson (Box 21)
  - Clippings, 1930-1939 (Box 21)
  - Cape Cod Canal (Box 21)
  - Cape Cod Canal, dissertation by William James Reid (Box 22)
  - Community Service Society, 1938-1947 (Box 22)
  - Colonial Dames New York, 1958 (Box 22)
  - Columbia University, 1950-1973 (Box 22)
  - East Harlem Health Center-Welfare Council (Box 22)
  - The Educational Dramatic League (The Educational Players), 1915-1920 (Box 22)
  - Edward VIII, 1919 (Box 22)
  - Elitch Gardens Theater, Denver, 1936-1952 (Box 22)
  - The Hundred Year Association of New York, Inc., 1932 (Box 22)
  - Lowell, Amy, 1964-1976 (Box 23)
  - Medicine and the changing order, The New York Academy of Medicine (Box 23)
  - Metropolitan Opera
    - 1938-1978 (Box 23)
    - 1949-1978 (Box 24)
  - Metropolitan Opera Association, 1938-1948 (Box 24)
  - Moravian Seminary and College for Women, PA, 1936 (Box 25)
  - Motion Picture Research Council, 1918-1934 (Box 25)
  - N--Miscellaneous, 1934-1953 (Box 25)
  - National Achievement Award, 1936-1944 (Box 25)
  - New York Historical Society, 1955-1961 (Box 25)
  - New York Public Library, 1937-1971 (Box 25)
  - New York University, 1933 (Box 25)
  - Northeast Harbor, ME, 1960-1976 (Box 25)
  - Nurses House, 1936-1972 (Box 25)
  - Nursing
    - New York Hospital, 1943-1953 (Box 26)
    - Practical Nurses, 1941-1944 (Box 26)
  - Perry family
    - 1948-1971 (Box 26)
    - 1943-1979 (Box 27)
  - Poetry, 1916-1973 (Box 27)
  - Poetry (Box 28)
  - Red Cross, 1910-1943 (Box 28)
  - Rochester, The University of, 1934 (Box 28)
  - Roosevelt, Edith Kermit Carow (Mrs Theodore), 1935-1948 (Box 28)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1914-1943 (Box 28)
  - Shakespeare Memorial Theater, 1927-1954 (Box 28)
  - Shaw, George Bernard, 1905-1962 (Box 28)
  - Speeches, 1933-1935 (Box 29)
  - Unemployment insurance, 1930-1935 (Box 29)
  - Unemployment relief, 1930-1933 (Box 29)
  - Unemployment relief (Box 30)
  - Welfare Council of New York City, 1935-1951 (Box 30)
  - Women's National Republican Club, 1951-1958 (Box 30)
  - Writings
    - Collected (Box 30)
    - Fabric of Memory (Box 30-31)
    - Christopher Rand, 1924-1931 (Box 31)
    - In the Next Room (Box 32)
    - That Man Gently (Box 32)
  - Yale University, 1948-1973 (Box 32)
  - Zangwill, Israel, 1904 (Box 32)
- Series III: Personal and Biographical, 1906-1975
  This series contains awards and honors, mementoes, photographs, articles and clippings on Mrs. Belmont. There are clippings, cards, and letters on her 100th birthday celebration as well as documentation on her death in 1979.
  - Awards, Certificates, Medal and Mortarboard (Box 33)
  - Bookplates, book catalog cards (Box 34)
  - Mementoes: coin, Book of Corinthians, Drawings, Menus (Box 34)
  - Photographs (Box 34)
  - Friends: Photos and articles (Box 34)
  - Pamphlets and programs, 1916-1953 (Box 34)
  - Pamphlets, Magazines, Programs, 1908-1978 (Box 35)
  - Clippings, 1906-1972 (Box 35)
  - 100th Birthday, 1978 (Box 35-37)
  - Death and funeral (Box 37)
- Series IV: Oversized Materials
  - Doctor of Humanities Hood from State College, Newark, NJ, 1966 (Box Flat Box 290)
  - Flag, Red Cross on white field (Box Flat Box 290)
  - 2 pencil drawings, signed
    - Boy, hands in pockets, 38x51cm (Box Flat Box 291)
    - Sailors, 39x51cm (Box Flat Box 291)
  - 1 print of ship by Chas Pear, 38x51cm (Box Flat Box 291)
  - Certificate awarding honorary Master of Arts signed by President Charles Seymour, 1948 (Box Flat Box 291)
  - Pencil and Crayon sketch of Metropolitan Opera House at Lincoln Center and fountain, 28x31cm (Box Flat Box 291)
  - Autographed poster with Mrs. Belmont’s photograph and "At Long Last, 100,000 Guild Members," 51x56cm (Box Flat Box 291)
  - Certificate granting honorary doctorate from Moravian Women’s College, 30x41cm, 1936 May 23 (Box Flat Box 291)
  - Post advertising "Illustrations of the Japan Expedition," 51x55cm (Box Flat Box 291)
  - Certificate of designation as delegate of the 16th international Red Cross Conference, signed by the Secretary of State Cordell Hull, 36x43cm, 1938 June (Box Flat Box 291)
  - Certificate of Honor to Eleanor R. Belmont by the American Red Cross, signed by President James F. Collins and by Chairman, 30x26cm, 1964 May 20 (Box Flat Box 291)
  - Certificate granting honorary doctorate signed by President Rush Rhees from the University of Rochester, 1934 (Box Flat Box 291)
  - Certificate of vote of appreciation to Mrs. August Belmont from the Executive Committee of the Emergency Employment Committee, 1931 April (Box Flat Box 291)
  - Certificate of Appreciation to Mrs. August Belmont from the Emergency Unemployment Committee for her achievements during the winter of 1931-1932 (Box Flat Box 291)
  - Certificate of appreciation to Mrs. August Belmont from the Executive Committee of the Emergency Unemployment Relief Committee for her work as chairman of the Woman’s Division during the winter of 1932-1933 (Box Flat Box 291)
  - Photograph of Leonard Hand parading in graduation robes, inscribed, 1953 February 15 (Box Flat Box 291)